Gary Paul Nabhan papers, 1969-
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series 2: Published materials, 1973-1998, Arrangement: Chronological with folders numbered according to bibliography of Dr. Nabhan.
  - Desert whirlwinds. Phoenix 25, 84-93. 1990, November (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - The evolution of a naturalist: finding the wild thread. Petroglyph 2, 5-7. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Healing the desert. Garden 14, 21-25. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Managing cultural resources in Sonoran desert biosphere reserves. Cultural Survival Quarterly 14(4), 26-30. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - New crops for small farmers in marginal lands? Wild chiles as a case study. Agroecology and Small Farm Development. Miguel A. Altieri and Susann B. Hecht, eds. Boca Raton: CRC Press. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - On tumbleweeds and dust. Northern Lights, 6(3), 11-13. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Brand, Janette C., B. Janelle Snow, Gary P. Nabhan, and A. Stewart Truswell. Plasma glucose and insulin responses to traditional Pima Indian meals. American Journal of Clinical Nutrition 51, 416-420. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Systematic and ecogeographic studies on crop genepools, 5: Wild phaseolus ecogeography in the Sierra Madre Occidental, Mexico: Areographic techniques for targeting and conserving species diversity. Rome, Italy: International Board for Plant Genetic Resources. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Nabhan, Gary P., Donna House, Humberto Suzan A., Wendy Hodgson, Luis Hernandez S. and Guadalupe Malda. Conservation and use of rare plants by traditional cultures of the U.S./Mexico borderlands. In Biodiversity: Culture, conservation, and ecodevelopment. M. Oldfield and J. Alcorn, eds. Boulder: Westview Press. (only 2 pages in folder). 1991 (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Cryptic cacti on the borderline. Orion 10(4), 26-31. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Fish, Suzanne K. and Gary P. Nabhan. Desert as context: the Hohokam environment. In Exploring the Hohokam: Prehistoric desert peoples of the American Southwest. G. J. Gumerman, ed. Albuquerque: University of New Mexico Press. (two copies) 1991 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Desert legumes as a nutritional intervention for diabetic indigenous dwells of arid lands. Arid Lands Newsletter 31, 11-13. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Nelson, Suzanne C., Gary P. Nabhan, and Robert H. Robichaux. Effects of water nitrogen and competition on growth yield and yield components of field-grown tepary bean. Experimental Agriculture 27, 211-219. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Dahl, Kevin, and Gary Paul Nabhan. From the grassroots up: plant genetic resource conservation by grassroots organizations in North America. Seed Savers Exchange. 1991, June 1 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Anderson, Kat, and Gary Paul Nabhan. Gardeners in Eden: Native American land management. Wilderness 55, 27-30. 1991, Fall (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Genetic resources of the U.S.-Mexican borderlands: wild relatives of crops, their uses and conservation. In Environmental Hazards and Bioresource Management in the United States-Mexico Borderlands. P. Ganster and H. Walter, eds. Los Angeles: UCLA Latin American Center Publications. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - The moveable O'odham feat of San Francisco. Native Peoples 4(2), 28- 34. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Restoring and re-storying the landscape. Restoration and Management Notes, 9, 3-4. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - A child's sense of wildness. Finding Home. Peter Sauer, ed. Boston: Beacon Press. 229-236. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 182)
  - Nabhan, Gary Paul, and Ted Fleming. The conservation of mutualisms. Species, 19, 32-34. (two copies) 1992, December (Box 4, Folder 183)
  - Desert rescuers. World Monitor, 5(7), 36-41 1992 (Box 4, Folder 186)
  - The fate of the desert on the line. World Monitor. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 188)
  - Hummingbirds and human aggression: A view from the high tanks. The Georgia Review 46(2), 213-232. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Native American cornucopia. Native Peoples Magazine, 5(3), 10-16. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 193)
  - Threatened Native American plants. Endangered Species Update, 9(11), 1-4. 1992 (Box 4, Folder 205)
  - Confessions from a sheep blind. Counting Sheep: 20 Ways of Seeing Desert Bighorn. G.P. Nabhan, ed. Tucson: The University of Arizona Press. 155-170. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Ironwood: Nurseries of the Sonoran Desert. Conservation International Members' Report, 11-13. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 214)
  - Songbirds, Truffles, and Wolves: An American Naturalist in Italy. New York: Pantheon Books. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 218)
  - Nabhan, Gary Paul, and Humberto Suzan. Boundary effects on endangered cacti and their nurse plants in and near a Sonoran Desert biosphere reserve. Occasional Papers in Conservation Biology, 1: Ironwood: An Ecological and Cultural Keystone of the Sonoran Desert. G. P. Nabhan and J. L. Carr, eds. Washington, DC: Conservation International. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 222)
  - The far outside. In Place of the Wild: A Wildland's Anthology. David Clarke Burks, ed. Washington, DC: Island Press. 19-27. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 225)
  - Nabhan, Gary Paul and John L. Carr. Occasional papers in conservation biology, 1: Ironwood: An ecological and cultural keystone of the Sonoran Desert. Washington, DC: Conservation International. 1994, April (Box 4, Folder 228)
  - Natural history crashes, resurfaces. Heart of the Land: Essays on Last Great Places. Joseph Barbato and Lisa Weinerman, eds. New York: Patheon. 86-91. 1994 (Box 4, Folder 229)
  - From the hidden garden. Journal of the Southwest 37(2), 401-415. 1995 (Box 4, Folder 240)
  - The Forgotten Pollinators. Washington DC: Island Press. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 257)
  - Nabhan, Gary, Angelo Joaquin, Jr., Nancy Laney, and Kevin Dahl. Sharing the benefits between indigenous communities and other conservators/users of plant genetic resources and ethnobotanical knowledge. In Valuing Local Knowledge: Indigenous People and Intellectual Property Rights. S. B. Brush and D. Stabinsky, eds. Covelo: Island Press. 186-208. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 263)
- Series 3: Miscellaneous, 1980-1994
  - Conference programs. 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Tucson Weekly; A Child's Sense of Wilderness. 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series 4: Monographs, 1993-1997
  - Chilies to Chocolate: Food the Americans Gave the World. 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sacred trusts: Essays on Stewardship and Responsibility. 1993 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Desert Legends: Re-storying the Sonoran Borderlands. 1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - The Geography of Childhood: Why Children Need Wild Places. 1994 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The Geography of Childhood: Why Children Need Wild Places.(Japanese edition) 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Canyons of Color: Utah's Slickrock Wildlands. 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - From the Islands' Edge: a Sitka Reader. 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Words from the Land: Encounters with Natural History Writing. 1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Writing it Down for James: Writers on Life and Craft. 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - The Late Great Mexican Border: Report from a Disappearing Line. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Resist Much Obey Little: Remembering Ed Abbey. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - American Nature Writing 1996. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Travelers' Tales: Food- a Taste of the Road. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Sierra Club Wetlands Reader: a Literary Companion. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Testimony: Writers of the West Speak on Behalf of Utah Wilderness. 1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Cultures of Habitat: on Nature, Culture, and Story. 1997 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Nature's Services: Societal Dependence on Natural Ecosystems. 1997 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Passing on a Sense of Place and Traditional Ecological Knowledge Between Generations: a Primer for Native American Museum Educators and Community- Based Cultural Education Projects. 1997 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Series 5: Production Materials
  - "Counting Sheep." (Box 6, Folder 1-6)
  - "Anatomy of a Scientific Discovery: Why Chilies are Hot." (Box 6, Folder 7-11)
- Series 6: Slides
  - Slides. (Box 6, Folder 12-17)